Guide to the John and Katherine Bakeless Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
John and Katherine Bakeless papers
1865-1966
MS 50
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5
(11 boxes)
Incoming correspondence, including letters from Irving Berlin, Aaron Copland and others, and edited typescripts for the books, Eyes of Discovery, Spies of the Revolution, In the Big Time, Lewis and Clark, Partners in Discovery, and Daniel Boone: Master of the Wilderness. Research materials, including copies of historical documents and photographs.The papers of Katherine Bakeless are also included in the collection.
Bakeless, John, 1894-1978
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of John E. and Katherine Bakeless, 1951-1962. Transferred from the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, 2011.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically.
Scope and Contents
The John and Katherine Bakeless Papers consist mainly of edited type-scripts for books they have written together and individually. Also included are correspondence, research materials and images and negatives used in publications.
Biographical / Historical
John Bakeless: born December 30, 1894, in Carlisle, Pennsylvania; graduate of Williams College; received M.A. and Ph.D. from Harvard; author and contributor to magazines; served as a military intelligence officer in the U.S. Army. Died August 8, 1978, in New Haven, Connecticut. Married Katherine Little on June 16, 1920.
Katherine Little Bakeless: born December 5, 1895, in Bloomsburg, Pennsylvania; author, teacher, pianist; collaborated with her husband on books. She also wrote two books for young readers on her own. Died July 29, 1992, in Seymour, Connecticut.
Authors, American; Novelists, American -- 20th Century; Authors; Historians; Bakeless, John, 1894-1978; Bakeless, Katherine Little, 1895-1992; Berlin, Irving, 1888-1989; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990
- Inventory
  - "Eyes of Discovery", 1950 (Box 1)
  - "Eyes of Discovery", 1950 (Box 2)
  - ["Turncoats, Traitors and Heroes" or "Spies of the Revolution"], 1959, 1962 (Box 3)
  - "Spies of the Revolution", 1962 (Box 3)
  - "Spies of the Revolution", 1962 (Box 4–6)
  - "In the Big Time", 1953, 1956 (Box 7)
  - "Story-Lives of American Composers", 1941 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Incoming Letters
    - Bauer Marion, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Berlin, Irving, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Camp, Edith Macy, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Carpenter, John Alden, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Clark, Victor S., 1941 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Copland, Aaron, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Currier, Richard, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Harris, Johana, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Jahn-Beer, Bertha, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - MacDowell, Marian (Nevins), 1940 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Macmillan Company, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Maisel, Edward M., 1941 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - [Metz], Virginia, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - The New Yorker, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Niles, Edward Abbe, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Pittsburgh Post-Gazette, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Stokes (Frederick A.) Company, 1940, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Wright, Dr. W. G., 1940 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Additional Material, 1865-1966, undated; Accession 2012-M-006
  - General Correspondence
    - Hawkins, Nana P., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Lancaster, Bruce and Stevenson, C.G., 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Voto, Bernard and others, 1945-1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Daniel Boone: Master of The Wilderness - research material and book illustrations, 1926-1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lewis and Clark, Partners in Discovery
    - Edited manuscript, Circa 1940s (Box 1, Folder 5-12)
    - Edited manuscript [separate draft], Circa 1940s (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
    - Edited manuscript [separate draft] and publisher correspondence, Undated, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Images with negatives, Circa 1940-1950 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Research material, 1865, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Research material and correspondence, 1951-1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Adventures of Lewis and Clark - edited manuscript (juvenile version), Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Spies of The Revolution - correspondence, 1930, 1961, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)